Tomasz Michał Kłosiński

+48 796 800 073 tomasz.klosinski@protonmail.ch For detailed list of projects visit: linkedin.com/in/tklosinski

I am M.A. graduate of IT (Databases) at Polish-Japanese Academy of Information Technology, B.A. graduate of Computer Science and B.A. graduate of Business Management, both held in English, at University of Lodz. I have been working in Linux world for last 4 years and I have been passionate Linux user for over 13 years. My current position is System Engineer in DevOps and Infrastructure teams at CERN Control Center.

SKILLS

Linux, Bash Ansible, Python, Vagrant, Chef, Ruby, Jenkins OpenStack, Eucalyptus, Amazon Web Services Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana MySQL, PostgreSQL Apache HTTPD, nginx, HAProxy Nagios, Zabbix, Monit Areas of Interest

DevOps, Continuous Delivery Cloud Computing, IT Infrastructure Agile Methodologies

EDUCATION

2010–2012
Polish-Japanese Academy of Information Technology (Warsaw)
Databases, M.A.
2008–2011
University of Lodz
Business Management, B.A.
2007–2010
University of Lodz
Computer Science, B.A.

CERIFICATION

Red Hat Certified Engineer (2014–2017)
Red Hat Certified System Administrator (2014–2017)

LANGUAGES

Polish (Native proficiency)
English (Full professional proficiency)
French (Elementary proficiency)

Previous Experience

2015–2016 CERN, *Project Associate* Geneva

At CERN Control Center I have been working in support team of over 2000 (OpenStack) VMs/desktops and servers (60% real-time kernel). Most of the servers that I have been taking care of were Linux machines providing the mission critical software (code base of over 10 MLOC of Java and 500 kLOC of C++ and C, structured in roughly 1000 projects) for the operation of LHC and other accelerators. Along with my daily support and troubleshooting tasks (for around 70 accelerator operators and 200 software developers), I have been involved in numerous activities in System Administration Modernisation project.

2014—2015 LINUX POLSKA, *Solution Architect* Warsaw

At Linux Polska I have worked on a continuous delivery system for building rpm packages. I have contributed also to the organization of the biggest Open Source event in Poland (which Linux Polska is co-organizing every year in May): Open Source Day.

2011–2014 IMPAQ, Software / System Engineer Warsaw

My career as a System Engineer at IMPAQ can be split into two periods. For first half year I have been member of a support team of RHEL-based telco applications for international cellular networks. For another 1.5+ year I have worked for Machine-to-Machine, Cloud Computing and Big Data Business Practice (Department).

2010–2011 Outbox, Junior Consultant Warsaw

At Outbox I have worked on the development of the CRM system based on Oracle PeopleSoft platform for Telekomunikacja Polska SA.